<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Just A Data Geek</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Just A Data Geek</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Burlington County, NJ, Part Two</title>
      <link>/2018/08/01/exploring-burlington-county-nj-part-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/01/exploring-burlington-county-nj-part-two/</guid>
      <description>Preface I share my blogposts on Twitter and LinkedIn. I also let a few friends know via email. The suggestions that I received were welcome. Some were things I had already planned to do and others I had not thought of. Now, allow me to continue…
 Exploring Burlington County, NJ Employment, continued… In my first post, I mentioned the autocorrlation of the data. I will post the autocorrelation graph here again, using the acf function in R:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Burlington County, NJ</title>
      <link>/2018/07/21/exploring-burlington-county-nj/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/21/exploring-burlington-county-nj/</guid>
      <description>Beginning An Exploration of Burlington County, NJ Early last year, my family and I moved back to the Philadelphia area. We settled in Burlington County, New Jersey. Details on the county and a bit about its history can be found on via Wikipedia.
I wanted to start this exploration with looking at county employment. I downloaded these data from the BLS QCEW website, which covers 2007 through 2017. Employment figures for the county for 2018 are not yet available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links</title>
      <link>/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/links/</guid>
      <description>This contains page contains links to other blogs and resources on the internet that I have found useful.
Blog Links Barter Is Evil Econbrowser: Analysis of current economic conditions and policy Econometrics Beat: David Giles’ Blog Hyndsight: A blog by Robert J Hyndman R-blogger Simply Statistics   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Thoughts On Bitcoin</title>
      <link>/2018/07/08/my-thoughts-on-bitcoin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/08/my-thoughts-on-bitcoin/</guid>
      <description>I enjoy listening to/reading the stories on the various business news outlets about cryptocurrencies – I have been casually reading about blockchain technology and its different applications, but that is not the focus of this post.
While I am not an “expert” on cryptocurrencies, I have come to the opinion that they are not really currencies. I see them as a commodity as opposed to a currency. Why?
Like some other commodities, it is “mined”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continued Introduction</title>
      <link>/2018/06/19/continued-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/19/continued-introduction/</guid>
      <description>This is a continuation to my first post just to see how things look using blogdown.
So… first, I’ll call one of the built in data sets:
library(tidyverse) library(hexSticker) data(cars) summary(cars) ## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.:19.0 3rd Qu.: 56.00 ## Max. :25.0 Max. :120.00 Now that the summary statistics are out of the way, here’s a quick plot using the ggplot2 package, part of the tidyverse:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 22:32:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Introduction My name is Rich Carpenter. I am an economist / data analyst with more than 9 years of experience, primarily with economic and financial data. I have a B.A. in Economics and Political Science and an M.S. in Applied Economics.
For more information about my background and experience, please visit my LinkedIn Profile.
You can also read older posts from my blog when I used Blogger.
Source and Theme Information This website was created using the blogdown package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introductory Post</title>
      <link>/2018/06/17/introductory-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/17/introductory-post/</guid>
      <description>After a bit of research and testing, I have decided to start using the blogdown package in R in order to continue blogging. With that change also comes the need to migrate my old blog from Google’s Blogger – that will be done over the summer and will probably a little bit of time since it’s not a straight forward process.
I have updated the About page on this blog, as well as links that refer to my information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/comment_policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/comment_policy/</guid>
      <description>Comment Policy The following rules are a slightly modified version of what is suggested by Disqus.
Please, try your damnedest to abide by them. Be polite, be professional. Thank you!
 The Rules: Keep it civil (aka “Don’t be a jerk!”) We’re going to get into the thick of a lot of heated discussions and that’s okay. These discussions often entail topics that we all personally care a lot about and will passionately defend.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>