<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Just A Data Geek</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Just A Data Geek</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Continued Introduction</title>
      <link>/2018/06/19/continued-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/19/continued-introduction/</guid>
      <description>This is a continuation to my first post just to see how things look using blogdown.
So… first, I’ll call one of the built in data sets:
library(tidyverse) library(hexSticker) data(cars) summary(cars) ## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.:19.0 3rd Qu.: 56.00 ## Max. :25.0 Max. :120.00 Now that the summary statistics are out of the way, here’s a quick plot using the ggplot2 package, part of the tidyverse: Finally, here’s my site logo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links</title>
      <link>/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 23:52:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/links/</guid>
      <description>This contains links to other blogs and resources that I have found useful.
Blog Links Barter Is Evil   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 22:32:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Introduction My name is Rich Carpenter. I am an economist / data analyst with more than 9 years of experience, primarily with economic and financial data. I have a B.A. in Economics and Political Science and an M.S. in Applied Economics. For more information about my background and experience, please visit my LinkedIn Profile.
Source and Theme Information This website was created using the blogdown package.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introductory Post</title>
      <link>/2018/06/17/introductory-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/17/introductory-post/</guid>
      <description>After a bit of research and testing, I have decided to start using the blogdown package in R in order to continue blogging. With that change also comes the need to migrate my old blog from Google’s Blogger – that will be done over the summer and will probably a little bit of time since it’s not a straight forward process.
I have updated the About page on this blog, as well as links that refer to my information.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>