<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Just A Data Geek</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Just A Data Geek</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>DJIA High-Low Spread</title>
      <link>/2019/01/02/djia-high-low-spread/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/02/djia-high-low-spread/</guid>
      <description>It is fun when insomnia, curiosity, and a good conversation lead to continuing research. Yesterday, I published a blog about the Dow Jones’ performance in 2018 link. One of my graduate program professors, David Flynn – whom I will shamelessly plug the blog of here: Barter Is Evil – replied about the relative calm period during the summer in the graph that showed daily volumes.
I became curious if the spread between the daily high and low price had any correlation with the daily volume.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 2018 Dow Jones Industrial Average&#39;s Performance</title>
      <link>/2019/01/01/the-2018-dow-jones-industrial-average-s-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/01/the-2018-dow-jones-industrial-average-s-performance/</guid>
      <description>What better than to start off the New Year with a blog?
This is a follow up to my previous blog about the Dow Jones Industrial Average (DJIA). The DJIA gave many people fits during the last quarter of 2018. Here is a look at its overall performance for the year:
Another view of the DJIA’s performance, this time looking at percent change and “level” change, respectively. These charts show values that are indexed to the first trading day of the year, 2 January 2018:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dow&#39;s Trick Or Treat</title>
      <link>/2018/10/31/dow-s-trick-or-treat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/31/dow-s-trick-or-treat/</guid>
      <description>The Dow Jones Industrial Average (DJIA) gave us an interesting, if not a little scary, performance this month. When we look at the difference in closing prices, we can see that it was mostly within a range of +/-500 points:
Another view is the percent change in the DJIA, indexing on 1 October 2018 and seeing how it performed:
On a similar note, I also looked at the year-to-date performance of the DJIA and noticed that volatility in the closing price occurred in two periods: the one we are experiencing now in October and the other that occurred in the February to April time period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distribution</title>
      <link>/2018/10/11/distribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/11/distribution/</guid>
      <description>Introductory Note There has been a lot going on at work and home, and my blogging has suffered from it. I am trying to get back into a regular blogging schedule. I will continue the Burlington County, NJ series later.
 The Dow Jones Has Had A Couple Of Bad Days… … but these are extreme events. Below is a graph of the distribution of the differences in market closes for the past year:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Burlington County, NJ, Part Two</title>
      <link>/2018/08/01/exploring-burlington-county-nj-part-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/01/exploring-burlington-county-nj-part-two/</guid>
      <description>Preface I share my blogposts on Twitter and LinkedIn. I also let a few friends know via email. The suggestions that I received were welcome. Some were things I had already planned to do and others I had not thought of. Now, allow me to continue…
 Exploring Burlington County, NJ Employment, continued… In my first post, I mentioned the autocorrelation of the data. I will post the autocorrelation graph here again, using the acf function in R:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Burlington County, NJ</title>
      <link>/2018/07/21/exploring-burlington-county-nj/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/21/exploring-burlington-county-nj/</guid>
      <description>Beginning An Exploration of Burlington County, NJ Early last year, my family and I moved back to the Philadelphia area. We settled in Burlington County, New Jersey. Details on the county and a bit about its history can be found on via Wikipedia.
I wanted to start this exploration with looking at county employment. I downloaded these data from the BLS QCEW website, which covers 2007 through 2017. Employment figures for the county for 2018 are not yet available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Thoughts On Bitcoin</title>
      <link>/2018/07/08/my-thoughts-on-bitcoin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/08/my-thoughts-on-bitcoin/</guid>
      <description>I enjoy listening to/reading the stories on the various business news outlets about cryptocurrencies – I have been casually reading about blockchain technology and its different applications, but that is not the focus of this post.
While I am not an “expert” on cryptocurrencies, I have come to the opinion that they are not really currencies. I see them as a commodity as opposed to a currency. Why?
Like some other commodities, it is “mined”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continued Introduction</title>
      <link>/2018/06/19/continued-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/19/continued-introduction/</guid>
      <description>This is a continuation to my first post just to see how things look using blogdown.
So… first, I’ll call one of the built in data sets:
library(tidyverse) library(hexSticker) data(cars) summary(cars) ## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.:19.0 3rd Qu.: 56.00 ## Max. :25.0 Max. :120.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introductory Post</title>
      <link>/2018/06/17/introductory-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/17/introductory-post/</guid>
      <description>After a bit of research and testing, I have decided to start using the blogdown package in R in order to continue blogging. With that change also comes the need to migrate my old blog from Google’s Blogger – that will be done over the summer and will probably a little bit of time since it’s not a straight forward process.
I have updated the About page on this blog, as well as links that refer to my information.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>