<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dow Jones on Just A Data Geek</title>
    <link>/tags/dow-jones/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dow Jones on Just A Data Geek</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/dow-jones/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dow&#39;s Trick Or Treat</title>
      <link>/2018/10/31/dow-s-trick-or-treat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/31/dow-s-trick-or-treat/</guid>
      <description>The Dow Jones Industrial Average (DJIA) showed gave us an interesting, if not a little scary, performance this month. When we look at the difference in closing prices, we can see that it was mostly within a range of +/-500 points:
Another view is the percent change in the DJIA, indexing on 1 October 2018 and seeing how it performed:
On a similar note, I also looked at the year-to-date performance of the DJIA and noticed that volatility in the closing price occured in two periods: the one we are experiencing now in October and the other that occured in the February to April time period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distribution</title>
      <link>/2018/10/11/distribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/11/distribution/</guid>
      <description>Introductory Note There has been a lot going on at work and home, and my blogging has suffered from it. I am trying to get back into a regular blogging schedule. I will continue the Burlington County, NJ series later.
 The Dow Jones Has Had A Couple Of Bad Days… … but these are extreme events. Below is a graph of the distribution of the differences in market closes for the past year:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>